Preliminary Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Roy Glah Papers, 1976-2002 and undated
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
J. Walter Thompson Company. Roy Glah papers 1976-2002 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
J. Walter Thompson Company.
10 Linear Feet 6000 Items
Founded in 1864 the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the largest and oldest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. Roy Glah was an executive with JWT beginning in 1957, holding positions of Vice President and Director of Finance and Administration.
Includes presentations, memos, development materials and reports related to advertising and the strategic planning for J. Walter Thompson, WPP, and various departments within JWT. Collection largely documents the latter part of Glah's career with JWT, as an executive in the New York Office. Also includes photographs, slides, audiocassettes, and videocassettes. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted.
Materials are closed to non-JWT researchers for 15 years from date of creation.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Roy Glah Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as gifts in 1999, 2000, 2004 and 2005.
Biographical Note
Biographical Chronology
1935 Dec. Born, Philadelphia, Penn.
1957 BFA, Cornell University Began work with JWT New York Office, Creative Department
Circa 1958-1960 Military service
1960 Media Department, JWT New York
1963 Account Representative, JWT New York
1964 JWT Amsterdam
Circa 1967 General Manager, JWT Amsterdam
1968 Account Supervisor, JWT New York
1972 Senior Vice President and Deputy Manager, JWT Tokyo
1974 Manager, JWT San Francisco
1977 Assistant to the Chairman, JWT New York
1982 Senior Vice President, Operations, JWT New York
1984 Deputy General Manager, JWT New York
1987 Elected Director, JWT
1988 Elected Executive Vice President, Finance and Administration, JWT/USA elected to U.S. Board of Directors
1990 Management Director, JWT
Collection Overview
Includes presentations, memos, development materials and reports related to advertising and the strategic planning for J. Walter Thompson, WPP, and various departments within JWT. Collection largely documents the latter part of Glah's career with JWT, as an executive in the New York Office. Also includes photographs, slides, audiocassettes, and videocassettes.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Glah, Roy, 1935-
Manning, Burt, 1931-
J. Walter Thompson Company
J. Walter Thompson Company. Amsterdam Office
J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office
J. Walter Thompson Company. San Francisco Office
J. Walter Thompson Company. Tokyo Office
Advertising agencies
Advertising agencies -- Management
Advertising agencies -- United States
Advertising executives
Advertising executives -- United States
Speeches, addresses, etc., American.
Presentations, Sales.
Videocassettes.
Slides
Audiocassettes
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections of the J. Walter Thompson Company Archives:
Biographical Information
Writings and Speeches
Loy Baxter Papers
Thomas Sutton Papers
Edward G. Wilson Papers
Contents of Collection
- Accession 99-057, 1991-1998, 7 boxes
  Accession (16,435 items, dated 1991-1998) features primarily administrative files for the World Wide Executive Group, a division of J. Walter Thompson responsible for executive training. The accession also includes orientation and motivational slide and video presentations, meeting minutes, as well as financial records and copies of speeches made by Burt Manning in 1992.
- Accession 99-141: Speeches and Presentations, 1992-1996 and undated, 6 boxes
  Series contains scripts of speeches and presentations given at meetings and special events, by Roy Glah, Burt Manning, Peter Schweitzer, Craig Davis and Adam Owett, among others. Also includes memos and other files related to JWT strategic plans. Original order of items was maintained.
  - AAAA acceptance speech, 1995 Apr. (Box 1)
  - American Business Press, electronic media speech, 1995 May
  - Strategic plan materials
    Includes presentations, memos, development materials and reports related to strategic planning for J. Walter Thompson, WPP, and various departments within JWT.
    - WPP, 3 year plan, 1993
    - JWT, 3 year plan, 1994-1996
    - JWT, 3 year plan, 1993-1995
    - Strategic plan summary, undated (Box 2)
    - WWEG strategic plan, 1996
    - JWT strategic plan, 1995-1996, (2 folders)
    - JWT strategic plan, staff memos, undated
    - Long range plan, 1991-1996
    - Long range planning strategy, 1991
  - Speeches and presentations (Box 3)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1992 Nov.
    - Mid-summer speech, 1995 Aug. (Davis)
    - Ascent of Woman, 1994
    - JWT kids presentation, 1994 (Goltz)
    - Beyond Trend, Search for the New, 1994 (Owett)
    - Big Idea, BOD, 1994
    - It's A Small World, 1993 (Schweitzer)
    - Electronic Superhighway, 1993
    - Human Resources, 1993 (Burns)
    - Globe, BOD/WWOG, 1993
    - Benefits program, 1993
    - Nestle, 1993 (Manning)
    - Asia Pacific managers speech, 1993
    - European general managers speech, 1993 (Manning)
    - HR conference, 1993 (Glah)
    - Asia Pacific general managers speech, 1993 (Manning)
    - Asia Pacific trip, 1993 (Schweitzer)
    - London Office, management and staff, Banner Year, 1993
    - Miscellaneous speech material on Change, undated
    - Abruption, 1995
    - Abruption in Coffee Advertising, 1995 (Manning)
    - Abruption: Quality and Cost in Advertising, 1995 (Manning) (Box 4)
      - (Includes presentation slides, development materials, videocassettes of Burt Manning speech Abruption, in Cebu, Philippines, 1995 Nov., and in Madrid, Spain, 1994 Oct.)
    - Board of Directors meeting, closing remarks, 1996 (Manning) (Box 5)
    - Abruption, address to UNIACC University, 1996 (Manning)
    - Abruption, Address to Chilean-American Chamber of Commerce, 1996 (Manning)
    - You Are Part of the Plan, 1996 (Manning)
    - Keynote Address, Club Circulo Creativo, Mexico City, 1996 (Manning)
    - Clean Slate: Lesson About Brand Building from the World's Newest Markets, 1996 (Berndt)
    - WPP, Board of Directors meeting, presentation materials, 1996, July 13
    - Good, the Bad, and the World Wide Web, 1996 (Manning)
    - All staff presentations to Asia Pacific, 1996 (Manning) (Box 6)
      - You Are Part of the Plan
      - Good, the Bad, and the World Wide Web
    - Duffs & Phelps presentation, 1996 (Manning)
    - AAF's silver medal, 1996 June (Manning)
    - WPP annual general meeting, 1996 June (Manning)
    - AAAA annual meeting, 1996 (Manning)
    - Branding of an Emotion: Kodak, 1996 (Manning)
    - AAAA annual meeting, chairman's address, 1996 (Manning)
    - San Miguel, Hong Kong Speech, 1995 (Manning)
    - Advertising in the Electronic Age, Oppenheimer Group, 1995
    - Creating Max Bandwidth, European tour version, 1996 (Manning)
- Accession 99-360: Meetings, 1987-1999, 10 boxes
  Series contains reports, memos and other files related to JWT management and financial meetings.
  - JWT management memos, 1988-1996 (Box 1)
  - JWT management projects, 1994-1997 (Box 2)
  - JWT management meetings, undated
    - 1997 (1995-1998) (Box 3)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 4)
    - 1998 (Box 5)
  - WPP annual reports and data, 1987-1999, JWT Rolex International advertising books, 1995-1997 (Box 6)
  - JWT financial analyst presentation at WPP meetings, 1992-1994 (Box 7)
  - JWT financial analyst presentation at WPP meetings, 1994-1996 (Box 8)
  - JWT WWEG meeting issues human resources, 1994-1995 (Box 9)
  - JWT miscellaneous company documents, JWT public relations-Frohlinger's report, 1991-1997 (Box 10)
- Accession 00-117, 1994-1998, 1 box
  Accession contains action summaries for 1994-1998 (.4 lin. ft.) of J. Walter Thompson Management Meetings covering Corporate and North America.
- Accession 2004-0049, 1976-2002, bulk [1990s], 14 boxes
  This accession contains 5250 items (8.4 lin. ft.) and includes primarily documents relating to the worldwide agency's meetings, including the OCE (Office of the Chief Executive), WEG (Worldwide Executive Group), and the Creative Council. Also contains files of speeches by JWT executives, presentations, credentials, videotapes, and materials relating to company CEO Burt Manning's projects.
  Restrictions on access: This accession is closed pending review by Technical Services.
  - Paper files (Box 1)
  - Paper files (Box 2)
  - Slides (Box 3)
  - VHS (Box 4)
  - Slides (Box 5)
  - Paper files (Box 6)
  - Slides, Umatic tape (Box 7)
  - Paper files (Box 8)
  - Slides, Umatic tapes (Box 9)
  - Umatic tapes (Box 10)
  - Audio cassette, VHS, Umatic tapes (Box 11)
  - Slides (Box 12)
  - Umatic tapes (Box 13)
  - Umatic tapes (Box 14)
- Accession 05-076, 1994-2002, 15 boxes
  Accession includes 3377 Items (9.9 lin. ft.) and comprises primarily speeches given by JWT CEOs Burt Manning and Chris Jones. Accession also contains presentations, slides, videos, and other files Roy Glah kept as part of his role in supporting JWT CEOs.
  - British-American Chamber of Commerce; Kodak, Shell, Global Marketplace speeches (Box 1)
  - JWT Strategic Plan 1999, Cuernavaca; WPP 3 YR Plan (Box 2)
  - General Reports, WPP Group Hopkins-WACL files (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous files; Speeches; Audiotapes, video, book, floppy disc (Box 4)
  - Video tapes (2 formats) (Box 5)
  - Videotapes (2 formats) (Box 6)
  - Person files; Comparative Advertising (Box 7)
  - Person files; Speeches (Box 8)
  - Bound files; loose papers (Box 10)
  - Abruption; Speeches; Loose files (Box 11)
  - Videotapes; Slide reel; Books; Magazines (Box 12)
  - Video tapes (Box 13)
  - Video tapes (Box 14)
  - Video tapes (Box 15)